# SHASHANK RAO

# **Art Director**

Portfolio link: http://shashnk.portfoliobox.net , https://shashank.pb.style

E-mail: suyiope@gmail.com, Mobile: +91 63698 85787, Address: Chennai-116, INDIA

## Summary: **■**

Have 9 yrs. of work experience with multidisciplinary skills, expertise with exemplary results in some of the world's most recognisable brands of Fashion and Retail, E-commerce, Business communication agency as an Art Director, Creative Manager and Senior Designer creating engaging and strategic integrated design and branding solutions.

Having worked both agency and client-side, I have a passion for branding and specialise in creating and developing meaningful brand experiences and leading the process from concept through to completion.

I acquired the academic excellence in the area of Accessory Design, Fashion Design, and Fashion Promotion from the top premium Design Institutes.

## **Core Competencies:**

- Translate business and marketing objectives into ideas that are clear, compelling, visually exciting, engaging and in-keeping with brand expression and standards.
- Demonstrate high-concept, cross-channel background and mindset, Strong problem solving skills, with a creative yet pragmatic approach to art direction.

#### Achievements:

- Received notable appreciations and recognitions from client and top managements for my work demonstrating successful business growth in all of my organizations.
- Honourable star ranking in previous organisation.
- Gold Medal Awardee in academic performance by former President of India A.P.J Abdul Kalam.

# Work Experience:

#### **NOVEMBER 2019 - PRESENT**

Currently searching for next job suiting my potential, upgrading my skills further by learning new software and programming language, also engaged in freelance design consultancy projects.

#### **AUGUST 2018 - NOVEMBER 2019**

RR DONNELLEY, Chennai, India

www.rrdonnelley.com

## Designation - Design Lead / Sr. Visualizer

- Provide senior level consulting services to clients related to plan strategy, design and team performance
- Effectively leading and mentoring team of 15 designers for world's top fin-tech conglomerate in Fortune 500 company.
- Successfully developed comprehensive client portfolio with emphasis on business expansion and brand recognition (specially in APAC region).
- Exponentially met and exceeded business goals by 37% within 6 months with major appreciation from our international clients .
- Admirably managed and art directed the overall creative look and consistency for all the branding and marketing collaterals.
- · Demonstrated thoughtful design, artistic skills and professional judgment in problem solving.

**Responsibilities:** Art Direction/ Design Management / Leadership / Client Communication / Time Management / Team management / Design Solution

#### April 2017 - August 2018

Synapse Information Services, Panjim, India

www.synapse.co

#### **Designation - Senior Designer**

- Successfully designed and was core designer for developing an Influential sleep solution brand **SleepX** for India's Top mattress brand Sleepwell.
- Effectively designed and managed all the Brand development, Product design, overall brand from concept to final product, including branding, packaging, logos, brand guidelines, product manual, accessory design, social media

promotions, gif animations and all other brand collaterals for one of the biggest client in company's history.

• Efficiently designed corporate branding and marketing collaterals for India's and International big names like Sleep Well, CPP, Kotak, SAP, Microsoft and ICICI.

**Responsibilities:** Art Direction/ Design Direction/ Creative Solution / Branding / Corporate Communication / Packaging Design / Client Meeting

#### **JULY 2015 - APRIL 2017**

Domaxy Info soft Pvt. Ltd., New Delhi, India

www.domaxy.com

## **Designation - Design Consultant**

- Effectively mentored designers for developing successful social media promotions, e-commerce collaterals, web pages, print collateral and email marketing templates, enhancing corporate image for clients.
- Engaged with various design projects for marketing collaterals including print and web based designs, banners, logos, product packaging design.
- Designed creative projects from India's leading brands like Royal Enfield, and Allen Solly.

Responsibilities: Design Consultation/ Outsourcing / Design Direction / E-commerce Design

#### MARCH 2015 - JULY 2015

Chazaar, Chennai, India / www.cbazaar.com

#### **Designation - Creative Manager**

- Successfully redesigned and improved the overall look of the brand, enhanced all its design collaterals effectively.
- Achieved 30% sales increase by designing and Creative direction on emails, landing pages, social media posts, and web banners, advertising and promotional e-commerce collaterals.
- Effectively managed and mentored 11 Designers on the Creative, Fashion and Photography team to inspire and help achieve consistent high quality creative outputs.
- Conceptualized and designed luxury packaging, style guide, brand book, comprehensive layouts, mood boards for the new brand look with quality control for ensuring accurate and consistent quality is received from third party suppliers.

**Responsibilities:** Art Direction / Design Management / Leadership / Presentations / Time Management / Talent Recruitment

#### JANUARY 2014 - FEBRUARY 2015

Urbantouch, Chennai, India

www.urbantouch.in

## **Designation - Creative Director**

- Effectively art directed the overall branding, enhanced the brand recognition and look.
- Expanded the brand and business to 5 top tier cities in southern part of India.
- Enhanced branding, print catalogue, product packaging, print ads, and promotional print materials.
- •Introduced trendy seasonal range of T-Shirts, Jeans, Polos, Shirts and Trousers enhancing consistency of design quality and visual Identity across all creative disciplines
- Maintained cross-functional and vendor relationships.

**Responsibilities:** Art Direction/ Design Management / Sampling / Sourcing / Production /Fashion Design / Packaging Design

#### JANUARY 2011 - DECEMBER 2013

Freelance, India

www.shashnk.portfoliobox.net

## **Designation - Freelance Design Consultant**

- Developed client's briefs and liaising directly with clients throughout the creative process.
- Collaborated with clients to create vision, conceive designs, and consistently meet deadlines and requirements.
- Designed presentations, print ads, documentations, brochures, advertorials, web banner, ads, billboards, logos, product packaging liaising with 3rd parties (developers / suppliers).

Responsibilities: Graphic Designing/ Design Consultation / Freelancing / Outsourcing

2005 DECEMBER – 2006 AUGUST M&B Footwear Pvt. Ltd, Noida, India

www.idfootwear.com

**Designation - Product and Graphic Designer for brand ID** 

- Coordinated / Designed / Developed the entire newly launch Accessory segment range of Belts, Socks, Bags, Packaging and Trims design for India's leading brand.
- Successfully created the strong identifica- tion of the brand (ID) in fashion accessory segment, increased the sales and lucrative expansion of the brand image.

**Responsibilities:** Ideation / Design Development / Sampling / Sourcing / Production / Graphics Design / Packaging Design / Logo Design / Trim Design.

#### 2005 MAY - 2005 SEPTEMBER

Rajesh Pratap Singh, New Delhi, India

www.rajeshpratapsingh.com

#### **Designation - Accessory Designer / Design Lead**

- Coordinated / Designed / Developed the Ladies Footwear Collection for LAKME INDIA FASHION WEEK 2005 for India's top and leading Fashion Brand.
- Introduced the new brand identity in fashion footwear segment with 7 years of highly successful sale of the designs.
- Successfully managed team of 5 in-house designers, Outsourced and Liaise with suppliers, developers, and creatives.

Responsibilities: Trend Analysis, Design Ideation / Development / Sourcing / Sampling / Production / Documentation

## Key Skills: ■

Leadership, Multitasking, Storytelling, Exploratory,

Analytical thinking, Time management, Teamwork, Mentoring, Decision-making, Organization skills, Adaptability, Fast Learner, Highly dependable, Flexibility, Effectual communication, Attention to detail, Multidisciplinary experience, Artistic innovation, Avant-Gard original ideas and creativity, Design Methodology, 'Can-do' attitude, Interpersonal skills, Strong aesthetic sense, High design quality

### Design Skills:

Art Direction, Graphic Design, Brand Development, Branding and Identity, Logo Design, Packaging Design, Visual Communications, Industrial Design (Product), Business Communications, Creative Communication, Multi-media Marketing Campaigns, Creative Concept Design and Development, Creative Briefs, Visual ideation, Visual Design, Print and Digital design, Presentation Skills, Info-graphics Design, Web Collaterals Design, Presentations Pitch, GIF Animation, Fashion and Accessory Design.

#### Education:

1. National Institute Of Fashion Technology, Chennai, India

(June 2002 - June 2005)

**Graduate Diploma in Accessory Design** 

Major: Lifestyle Product Design, Footwear and Leather Goods Design

2. Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology, Melbourne, Australia

(May 2008 - Nov 2008)

(Exchange Program)

Major: Fashion Design (Women's wear Pret), Fashion Promotion and Branding

3. National Institute of Design, Ahmedabad, India

(July 2007 - July 2010)

**Post Graduate Study** 

Apparel Design

## **Software Knowledge:**

- Adobe Illustrator CC15 Photoshop, Indesign, Lightroom
- Pixelmator
  MS Word/Power Point
- · Operating System: MAC / PC

## Personal Information:

DOB: 26/8/1982, Gender: Male, Nationality: Indian Marital status: Single, Native: Varanasi, INDIA,

Language: Hindi and English (Fluent in Reading, Writing and Speaking)

Portfolio link: http://shashnk.portfoliobox.net , https://shashank.pb.style E-mail: suyiope@gmail.com, Mobile: +91 63698 85787, Address: Chennai-116, INDIA